<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Skitraverse - info</title><link href="https://skitraverse.com/" rel="alternate"/><link href="https://skitraverse.com/feeds/info.atom.xml" rel="self"/><id>https://skitraverse.com/</id><updated>2026-01-07T09:17:16.740184+01:00</updated><entry><title>Disclaimer / Data Protection</title><link href="https://skitraverse.com/info/disclaimer/" rel="alternate"/><published>2023-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-31T16:51:59.152533+02:00</updated><author><name>Brian J. Oney</name></author><id>tag:skitraverse.com,2023-01-01:/info/disclaimer/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div id="outline-container-orgbb60d9a" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgbb60d9a"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The contents of this website were carefully created by Brian J. Oney.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgad30694" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgad30694"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt; Definitions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-2"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The author is Brian J. Oney.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge, hints, suggestions are used for the further education of the readers with the intention of using them in winter sports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The organization is called Snowy Experiments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="outline-container-orgbb60d9a" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgbb60d9a"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The contents of this website were carefully created by Brian J. Oney.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgad30694" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgad30694"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt; Definitions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-2"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The author is Brian J. Oney.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge, hints, suggestions are used for the further education of the readers with the intention of using them in winter sports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The organization is called Snowy Experiments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The male gender in the following text applies to all genders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A user is a person who retrieves information from this website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org868bd39" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org868bd39"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;3.&lt;/span&gt; Liability for Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Information is provided on this website for educational purposes only. This
information is based on scientific reports and on the experience of the
author. This information is used under the own responsibility and risk of
the user. In the event of accidents and injuries, the user discharges Brian
J. Oney from any and all claims or causes of action, known or unknown,
arising out of negligence. Insurance is the responsibility of the user.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgfa0fdcd" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgfa0fdcd"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;4.&lt;/span&gt; Liability for links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-4"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Our content contains links to external websites of third parties, and we have
no influence on their contents. Therefore, we can also not be held responsible
for this third-party content, and we assume no liability. For the contents of
the linked pages the respective providers or operators of the pages are always
responsible.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgcbad40e" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgcbad40e"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;5.&lt;/span&gt; Copyright&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-5"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The content and works on these pages created by the site operators
are subject to Swiss copyright law. The duplication, processing,
distribution and any kind of exploitation outside the limits of
copyrights require the written consent of the respective author
or creator. Downloads and copies of this page are only for private,
non-commercial use permitted. As far as the content on this page
were not created by the operator, the copyrights of third parties
observed. In particular, third-party content is treated as such
marked. If you still notice a copyright infringement
If you become aware of this, we ask that you inform us accordingly.
As soon as we become aware of legal violations, we will remove such content immediately
remove.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org31f5cac" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org31f5cac"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;6.&lt;/span&gt; Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-6"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The use of our website is usually without personal information
dates possible. Insofar as personal data is collected on our website
are, as far as possible, always on a voluntary basis
(e.g. own transmission of your data). This data will be without your
express consent not passed on to third parties.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We would like to point out that data transmission on the Internet (e.g. with
the communication via e-mail) may have security gaps. A complete protection
of data against access by third parties is not possible.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The use of contact data published as part of the imprint obligation
by third parties to send unsolicited advertising and
information materials are hereby expressly rejected. The operators
the sides expressly reserve the right to take legal action in the event of
unsolicited sending of advertising information, such as spam e-mails.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="info"/><category term="legal"/><category term="privacy"/></entry><entry><title>Datenschutz / Impressum</title><link href="https://skitraverse.com/info/impressum/" rel="alternate"/><published>2023-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-31T16:51:59.164533+02:00</updated><author><name>Brian J. Oney</name></author><id>tag:skitraverse.com,2023-01-01:/info/impressum/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div id="outline-container-orgbd45f22" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgbd45f22"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; Impressum&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Der Inhalt dieser Webseite wurde von Brian J. Oney mit grösster Sorgfalt erstellt. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgd8c6cc2" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgd8c6cc2"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt; Definitionen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-2"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Der Autor ist Brian J. Oney.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wissen, Hinweise, Vorschläge dienen Weiterbildung der Leser mit Absicht der Anwendung im Wintersport&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Die Organisation nennt sich Skitraverse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Das männliche Geschlecht im folgenden Text gilt für alle …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="outline-container-orgbd45f22" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgbd45f22"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; Impressum&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Der Inhalt dieser Webseite wurde von Brian J. Oney mit grösster Sorgfalt erstellt. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgd8c6cc2" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgd8c6cc2"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt; Definitionen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-2"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Der Autor ist Brian J. Oney.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wissen, Hinweise, Vorschläge dienen Weiterbildung der Leser mit Absicht der Anwendung im Wintersport&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Die Organisation nennt sich Skitraverse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Das männliche Geschlecht im folgenden Text gilt für alle Geschlechter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ein Nutzer ist eine Person die von dieser Webseite Information holt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org575ea9e" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org575ea9e"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;3.&lt;/span&gt; Haftung für Angebot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Auf dieser Webseite werden zu Ausbildungszwecken Informationen angeboten. Diese
Information basieren auf wissenschaftliche Berichte sowie auf Erfahrung des
Autors. Der Einsatz dieser Informationen erfolgt unter der
eigenen Verantwortung und Gefahr. Im Falle von Unfällen und Verletzungen haftet der
Nutzer. Versicherung ist Sache des Teilnehmers.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org61598cc" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org61598cc"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;4.&lt;/span&gt; Haftung für Inhalte&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-4"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Die Inhalte unserer Seiten wurden mit grösster Sorgfalt erstellt. Für die
Richtigkeit, Vollständigkeit und Aktualität der Inhalte können wir jedoch
keine Gewähr übernehmen. Verpflichtungen zur Entfernung oder Sperrung der
Nutzung von Informationen nach den allgemeinen Gesetzen bleiben hiervon
unberührt. Eine diesbezügliche Haftung ist jedoch erst ab dem Zeitpunkt der
Kenntnis einer konkreten Rechtsverletzung möglich. Bei Bekanntwerden von
entsprechenden Rechtsverletzungen werden wir diese Inhalte umgehend entfernen.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgb037b5b" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgb037b5b"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;5.&lt;/span&gt; Haftung für Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-5"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unser Angebot enthält Links zu externen Webseiten Dritter, auf deren Inhalte
wir keinen Einfluss haben. Deshalb können wir für diese fremden Inhalte auch
keine Gewähr übernehmen. Für die Inhalte der verlinkten Seiten ist stets der
jeweilige Anbieter oder Betreiber der Seiten verantwortlich. Die verlinkten
Seiten wurden zum Zeitpunkt der Verlinkung auf mögliche Rechtsverstösse
überprüft. Rechtswidrige Inhalte waren zum Zeitpunkt der Verlinkung nicht
erkennbar. Eine permanente inhaltliche Kontrolle der verlinkten Seiten ist
jedoch ohne konkrete Anhaltspunkte einer Rechtsverletzung nicht zumutbar. Bei
Bekanntwerden von Rechtsverletzungen werden wir derartige Links umgehend
entfernen.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgad0ca8c" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgad0ca8c"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;6.&lt;/span&gt; Urheberrecht&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-6"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Die durch die Seitenbetreiber erstellten Inhalte und Werke auf diesen Seiten
unterliegen dem Schweizerischen Urheberrecht. Die Vervielfältigung, Bearbeitung,
Verbreitung und jede Art der Verwertung ausserhalb der Grenzen des
Urheberrechtes bedürfen der schriftlichen Zustimmung des jeweiligen Autors
bzw. Erstellers. Downloads und Kopien dieser Seite sind nur für den privaten,
nicht kommerziellen Gebrauch gestattet. Soweit die Inhalte auf dieser Seite
nicht vom Betreiber erstellt wurden, werden die Urheberrechte Dritter
beachtet. Insbesondere werden Inhalte Dritter als solche
gekennzeichnet. Sollten Sie trotzdem auf eine Urheberrechtsverletzung
aufmerksam werden, bitten wir um einen entsprechenden Hinweis. Bei
Bekanntwerden von Rechtsverletzungen werden wir derartige Inhalte umgehend
entfernen.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgc2c27e2" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgc2c27e2"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;7.&lt;/span&gt; Datenschutz&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-7"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Die Nutzung unserer Webseite ist in der Regel ohne Angabe personenbezogener
Daten möglich. Soweit auf unseren Seiten personenbezogene Daten erhoben
werden, erfolgt dies, soweit möglich, stets auf freiwilliger Basis
(beispielsweise eigene Sendung Ihrer Daten). Diese Daten werden ohne Ihre
ausdrückliche Zustimmung nicht an Dritte weitergegeben.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Wir weisen darauf hin, dass die Datenübertragung im Internet (z.B. bei der
Kommunikation per E-Mail) Sicherheitslücken aufweisen kann. Ein lückenloser
Schutz der Daten vor dem Zugriff durch Dritte ist nicht möglich.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Der Nutzung von im Rahmen der Impressumspflicht veröffentlichten Kontaktdaten
durch Dritte zur Übersendung von nicht ausdrücklich angeforderter Werbung und
Informationsmaterialien wird hiermit ausdrücklich widersprochen. Die Betreiber
der Seiten behalten sich ausdrücklich rechtliche Schritte im Falle der
unverlangten Zusendung von Werbeinformationen, etwa durch Spam-Mails, vor.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="info"/><category term="legal"/><category term="privacy"/></entry><entry><title>About Brian J. Oney</title><link href="https://skitraverse.com/info/my-story/" rel="alternate"/><published>2023-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2026-01-07T09:17:16.740184+01:00</updated><author><name>Brian J. Oney</name></author><id>tag:skitraverse.com,2023-01-01:/info/my-story/</id><summary type="html">Swiss-certified alpine ski guide and first person to complete a winter ski traverse of the Continental Divide Trail from Mexico to Canada.</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="outline-container-orge4bfa66" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orge4bfa66"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; About Brian&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'm a Swiss-certified alpine ski guide who completed the first winter ski traverse of the Continental Divide Trail from Mexico to Canada. But like most expeditions, this one started long before the first step.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org5364eeb" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org5364eeb"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-3"&gt;1.1.&lt;/span&gt; The Journey to the Continental Divide&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-1-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
My relationship with snow began predictably enough: as a kid sledding off the carport roof, one cross-country ski outing with the Boy Scouts, and sporadic snowboarding in the '90s. What changed was college, where I joined the Weber State University Snowboard team and discovered that mountains weren't just playgrounds—they were classrooms.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In 2012, after moving to Switzerland, I started splitboarding in the Alps. The transition from resort riding to backcountry touring opened a new world. By 2015, I was ascending high Alpine peaks in winter and completing multi-day hut-to-hut traverses, learning to read avalanche terrain and weather patterns that could kill you if you got them wrong.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orga23aa2e" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="orga23aa2e"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-3"&gt;1.2.&lt;/span&gt; Certifications &amp;amp; Training&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-1-2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The Swiss Alpine Club doesn't hand out certifications lightly. I earned mine through years of technical training and field experience:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;2017:&lt;/b&gt; Swiss Alpine Club Backcountry Ski Guide Certification (Tourenleiter I)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;2021:&lt;/b&gt; Swiss Alpine Club Alpine Ski Guide Certification (Tourenleiter II)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;2021:&lt;/b&gt; Transitioned from splitboarding to skiing for better efficiency on long traverses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
These weren't just pieces of paper. They represented hundreds of days in avalanche terrain, navigation in whiteout conditions, rescue training, and the judgment to turn around when the mountain says no.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org57e0cc8" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org57e0cc8"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-3"&gt;1.3.&lt;/span&gt; Testing Limits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-1-3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;2020-2021:&lt;/b&gt; Started pushing into multi-week snow camping traverses, carrying everything needed for extended self-supported travel.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;February-March 2022:&lt;/b&gt; Solo ski traverse of Bulgaria's Pirin and Rila Mountains. Multiple routes, complete winter conditions, alone. This was the proving ground—could I handle isolation, route-finding, and decision-making with no backup?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;November 2022 - June 2023:&lt;/b&gt; The Continental Divide. Started at the Mexican border on November 21st, 2022. Finished at Devil's Thumb Trailhead, Colorado, on June 3rd, 2023. 194 days. 2,200 miles on skis. Solo except for the Montana-Canada section with my partner Lukas. First winter traverse of the Continental Divide from Mexico to Canada.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org6d62dfd" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org6d62dfd"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-3"&gt;1.4.&lt;/span&gt; What Didn't Work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-1-4"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;2025:&lt;/b&gt; Attempted ski traverses in Japan and Iceland. Both failed due to circumstances beyond my control. Mountains don't care about your plans, and sometimes the answer is no.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orga523a3c" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="orga523a3c"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-3"&gt;1.5.&lt;/span&gt; What I Do Now&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-1-5"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I live in Rüschlikon, Switzerland, with my wife. I continue to guide in the Alps, contribute to climate change mitigation efforts, and plan future expeditions.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The story is still being written. Preferably in the snow.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org9596f4d" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org9596f4d"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-3"&gt;1.6.&lt;/span&gt; Contact &amp;amp; Credentials&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-1-6"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swiss Alpine Club Tourenleiter I &amp;amp; II certified&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Author of &lt;i&gt;A Wild Calling: My Winter Ski Traverse of the Continental Divide&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based in Rüschlikon, Switzerland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Available for talks, interviews, and expedition consulting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://skitraverse.com/winter-cdt-book/winter-cdt-book/"&gt;Read about the book&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://skitraverse.com/winter-cdt/winter-cdt-trip-report/"&gt;Full Continental Divide trip report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type="application/ld+json"&gt;
{
  "@context": "https://schema.org",
  "@type": "Person",
  "name": "Brian J. Oney",
  "givenName": "Brian",
  "familyName": "Oney",
  "additionalName": "Johannes",
  "url": "https://skitraverse.com",
  "image": "https://skitraverse.com/img/book-cover.jpg",
  "jobTitle": "Alpine Ski Guide",
  "description": "Swiss-certified alpine ski guide and first person to complete a winter ski traverse of the Continental Divide Trail",
  "knowsAbout": [
    "Alpine Skiing",
    "Winter Mountaineering",
    "Backcountry Navigation",
    "Avalanche Safety",
    "Long-distance Ski Expeditions",
    "Route Planning",
    "Self-supported Winter Travel"
  ],
  "hasCredential": [
    {
      "@type": "EducationalOccupationalCredential",
      "credentialCategory": "certification",
      "name": "Backcountry Ski Guide Certification (Tourenleiter I)",
      "recognizedBy": {
        "@type": "Organization",
        "name": "Swiss Alpine Club"
      },
      "dateCreated": "2017"
    },
    {
      "@type": "EducationalOccupationalCredential",
      "credentialCategory": "certification",
      "name": "Alpine Ski Guide Certification (Tourenleiter II)",
      "recognizedBy": {
        "@type": "Organization",
        "name": "Swiss Alpine Club"
      },
      "dateCreated": "2021"
    }
  ],
  "alumniOf": {
    "@type": "Organization",
    "name": "Weber State University"
  },
  "address": {
    "@type": "PostalAddress",
    "addressLocality": "Rüschlikon",
    "addressCountry": "Switzerland",
    "postalCode": "8803"
  },
  "nationality": {
    "@type": "Country",
    "name": "United States"
  },
  "award": [
    "First winter ski traverse of the Continental Divide Trail (Mexico to Canada, 2022-2023)",
    "First winter ski traverse of Bulgaria's Pirin and Rila Mountains (2022)"
  ],
  "sameAs": [
    "https://skitraverse.com"
  ]
}
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="info"/><category term="about"/><category term="author"/><category term="bio"/></entry></feed>