<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Skitraverse - tips</title><link href="https://skitraverse.com/" rel="alternate"/><link href="https://skitraverse.com/feeds/tips.atom.xml" rel="self"/><id>https://skitraverse.com/</id><updated>2025-08-31T20:00:11.095584+02:00</updated><entry><title>My approach to and style of ski traverses</title><link href="https://skitraverse.com/tips/approach-and-style/" rel="alternate"/><published>2023-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-31T16:51:59.148533+02:00</updated><author><name>Brian J. Oney</name></author><id>tag:skitraverse.com,2023-01-01:/tips/approach-and-style/</id><summary type="html">

&lt;div id="outline-container-org5fb0f87" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org5fb0f87"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; Expedition style&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Let me establish two approaches to a ski traverses longer than a week, as I
understand them. The classical approach is similar to a polar expedition. This
expedition style entails harnessing a heavy (&amp;gt;1kg) sled that cannot be
practically carried, taking a lot of liquid fuel, a …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">

&lt;div id="outline-container-org5fb0f87" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org5fb0f87"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; Expedition style&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Let me establish two approaches to a ski traverses longer than a week, as I
understand them. The classical approach is similar to a polar expedition. This
expedition style entails harnessing a heavy (&amp;gt;1kg) sled that cannot be
practically carried, taking a lot of liquid fuel, a smaller pack, and
making an average progress each day of 8-40km, summing up and down. Ski tours
are loops starting at basecamp when the time is right.  Passable terrain is
limited by the skill to handle the heavy sled, but is practically limited to
mellow terrain with few obstacles. The range of total distances covered can be
very high (1000km), strongly depending on conditions. Weight is always an
issue, but there's a sled. This approach is great for long-lived basecamps in
remote places.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org0307244" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org0307244"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt; Alpine style&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I will focus here on the application of alpinism's 'light and fast' style to
ski traverses. I'll call them alpine style ski traverses.  The key
difference between expedition style and alpine style is speed. Alpine style
assumes speedy sustained progress, typically twice as fast as expedition
style. The choices of gear are important, as weight heavily influences
speed. Training requires a solid aerobic base, upon which a lot of training
with a heavy pack can be done in the off season.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
Alpine style ski traverses entail carrying everything in a large, yet light and
compressible backpack, possibly with a small (&amp;lt;1kg) packable sled (e.g. a
boggy, see &lt;a href="http://www.johnbaldwin.ca/trip-planning-toboggan.asp"&gt;http://www.johnbaldwin.ca/trip-planning-toboggan.asp&lt;/a&gt;) when
starting.  Average progress each day can vary wildly from 10km to 50km per
day, summing up and down. Passable terrain is limited by each group member's
ability to ski with a loaded pack. The range of distances to be covered are
moderate to high (100 to 500km) between resupplies, are limited by the speed
of the group and their ability to carry the sustaining food and fuel, and, of
course, are strongly dependent on conditions. Weight is a core issue.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The alpine style allows access to the much steeper terrain. Thinking of
forward progress in distance is not useful. I'll define an 'alpine unit' based
on the military approximation, but is taught in certain German circles as a
"Leistungskilometer" (effort kilometer). I was taught the same concept but the
word "Einheit" (unit) was used.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The concept of an alpine unit hinges on the assumption that one kilometer of
distance requires the same amount of effort and time as a hundred meters of
altitude gain.  &lt;b&gt;The alpine unit equates 100m vertical gain with 1000m
distance.&lt;/b&gt; A handy calculation for imperial units is difficult on the fly, so
roughly convert vertical feet to meters. Also, overlaying the UTM grid (1km by
1km) on a map allows for relatively precise determination of distance, without
the aid of digital technology. A good first approximation for the time
necessary for an alpine unit is 15 minutes or 4 units per hour. Although
individuals may be much faster, the time taken for a unit must be
constantly observed and used for planning forward progress both in the short
and long terms. Note, an old and wise mountain guide says that this equation
needs modification when the terrain is very flat (&amp;lt;5°) or very steep
(&amp;gt;35°). When it is flat, only consider the distance, when it is steep, only
consider the height.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The number of alpine units sustained per day over the course of a week is an
important result of reflection when planning the next ski traverse. A first
approximation of this sustained progress could be half of the normal alpine
units done on a day's ski tour. If you are strong with a heavy pack, take 3/4
of the speed on a day's ski tour. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Alpine style ski traverses allow for continuous replanning of the route, fast
exits, avoidance or mitigation of bad weather, and, my favorite, complete
immersion in a mountain range. This is the approach of the pioneers of ski
traverses, light and therefore fast and nimble. Bill Briggs did not have a
sled on the Bugaboo to Rogers Traverse. With the constantly improving
lightweight gear, improving map material, denser weather observation networks,
improved remote sensing data availability and access, this practice can become
safer and more enjoyable with time, especially when experience allows you to
whittle down your kit, and you condition yourself further.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-orge5df879" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orge5df879"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;3.&lt;/span&gt; My alpine style ski traverses&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In my case, my pack can weigh a maximum of about 25kg, including skis, and I
am still having fun. I aim for 40 units per day, which assumes some poor
conditions and some good conditions for progress. My daily progress on my ski
traverse in Bulgaria averaged at about alpine 45 units per day sustained over
8 days, including a rest day. That's not fast, but it suffices to cover
considerable ground (360 alpine units total). I used 106mm wide skis
and freeride bindings. I could have been faster with narrower skis, lighter
bindings, or scale-based skis. I have much room to learn and improve.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I am thankful for the concise book on winter mountaineering 'Bergsport Winter'
in German. I am most thankful for all my mentor's and friend's guidance and
patience. They were pivotal in aiding me to develop the necessary skills of
determining avalanche risk, orienteering in all conditions, detailed map study
and route planning, as well as little bits of information to make prolonged
stays in the often harsh winter landscape enjoyable. They continue to be very
helpful and good company. Thank you!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="tips"/><category term="techniques"/><category term="safety"/><category term="philosophy"/></entry><entry><title>Ski traverses in Bulgaria</title><link href="https://skitraverse.com/tips/bulgaria-2022/" rel="alternate"/><published>2023-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-31T20:00:11.091584+02:00</updated><author><name>Brian J. Oney</name></author><id>tag:skitraverse.com,2023-01-01:/tips/bulgaria-2022/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;div id="outline-container-org9001cf7" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org9001cf7"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; Summary from 2022 Trip&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mid-February to mid-March&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Pirin and Rila mountains offer the best terrain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sun is strong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Snowline can be high 1000m&amp;#x2013;1800m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wind is constantly blowing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Due to the wind, Good conditions in the Alpine are rare.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most terrain is gentle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treeline is high. &lt;i&gt;Pinus mura …&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;div id="outline-container-org9001cf7" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org9001cf7"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; Summary from 2022 Trip&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mid-February to mid-March&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Pirin and Rila mountains offer the best terrain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sun is strong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Snowline can be high 1000m&amp;#x2013;1800m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wind is constantly blowing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Due to the wind, Good conditions in the Alpine are rare.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most terrain is gentle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treeline is high. &lt;i&gt;Pinus mura&lt;/i&gt; can be found up to 2500m, but is stunted at this elevation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forests grow thick. Large wild rose bushes are common. Fallen branches are everywhere. Bushwhacking is common, and care is needed when skiing in the forest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Map data is readily available and can be high quality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hut infrastructure and hut culture is great, often better than that of the Alps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No helicopter rescue is available as of 2022.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wildlife sticks to lower elevations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Snow tends to be a little wet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The book &lt;a href="https://www.skiingthebalkans.com/"&gt;Skiing the Balkans&lt;/a&gt; by Dimitar Dimitrov is very useful as an introduction to backcountry skiing in Bulgaria.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buses, trains, and hitchhiking (if you speak Bulgarian) work well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div id="outline-container-org2896bca" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org2896bca"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt; Infrastructure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It is often unclear if a certain hut has a warden at a certain
time. Unserviced huts, which are easily accessible e.g. without special
equipment such as those close to ski resorts (Banderitsa Hut) are often
locked. Unserviced alpine huts almost always are unlocked and have a room with
many beds, blankets, and a wood stove, with plenty of wood. Good practice is
to leave the facilities more orderly than found, and slip some money under the
locked door of the warden's office.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Due to the uncertainty and difficulty of a rescue, a conservative approach to
these mountains is advised. No helicopter rescue is available as of 2022.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org3021584" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org3021584"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;3.&lt;/span&gt; Map Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Maps of slope angle classes can be inaccurate, maybe due to the lack of ground
truth data, but are sufficient. I recommend CalTopo because it has better slope class angles in the Pirin and Rila Mountains than competing offers, as of writing this in late 2022.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Iskar Tour maps are the best printed option. However, they are very delicate
for use en route, and require forethought how to stow and access them
practically. They can be difficult to obtain outside of Bulgaria.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The website bgmountains.org has routinely updated map tiles for offline use
with a mapping app such as CalTopo. These are the most detailed electronic
maps for navigating routes in Bulgaria. The download is free, so a donation is
recommended. They also offer a map tiling service at &lt;a href="https://kade.si"&gt;https://kade.si&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
https://bgmtile.kade.si/{Z}/{X}/{Y}.png 
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The best combination for mapping data, as of writing this in late 2022, would be
to add this tiling service to your CalTopo layers and combine that with
CalTopo's most accurate slope angle class. A wiser me takes PDF printouts of my
CalTopo custom maps, when CalTopo or my phone fails to work.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
For example, my notes help me to hit the ground running, as well as &lt;a href="https://caltopo.com/m/6JPNRK1"&gt;share&lt;/a&gt; them with you.
&lt;a href="https://caltopo.com/m/6JPNRK1"&gt;https://caltopo.com/m/6JPNRK1&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-orgc5ce940" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgc5ce940"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;4.&lt;/span&gt; Wildlife&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-4"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Wolves have cohabitated Bulgaria with humans since the beginning of our
time. Wolves fear and avoid humans. Likewise, humans fear and avoid
wolves. Mind your manners, and you may have a problem with a dog, but not a
wolf.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I may have seen one wolf, which was interested in a dog, which was following
me and had a limp. The wolf was not interested in me.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I saw a few chamois. Otherwise, I saw many tracks of boar, deer, wolves, but no bear tracks.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="tips"/><category term="international"/><category term="report"/><category term="planning"/></entry><entry><title>Skills for ski traversal</title><link href="https://skitraverse.com/tips/skills-and-training/" rel="alternate"/><published>2023-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-31T20:00:11.095584+02:00</updated><author><name>Brian J. Oney</name></author><id>tag:skitraverse.com,2023-01-01:/tips/skills-and-training/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;div id="outline-container-org3e4df14" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org3e4df14"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgea0afb5" class="outline-4"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="orgea0afb5"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-4"&gt;1.0.1.&lt;/span&gt; Wilderness First Responder&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-4" id="text-1-0-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Many backcountry areas are very remote, and more so during Winter. We need to be
able to take care of one another. That means having the WFR-certification. Swiss tour
guides only need a first aid course, oddly, but that is likely because …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;div id="outline-container-org3e4df14" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org3e4df14"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgea0afb5" class="outline-4"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="orgea0afb5"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-4"&gt;1.0.1.&lt;/span&gt; Wilderness First Responder&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-4" id="text-1-0-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Many backcountry areas are very remote, and more so during Winter. We need to be
able to take care of one another. That means having the WFR-certification. Swiss tour
guides only need a first aid course, oddly, but that is likely because medical
assistance here in Switzerland arrives 8-12 minutes(!) after being alerted, if
the weather allows.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org2bfe8d9" class="outline-4"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="org2bfe8d9"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-4"&gt;1.0.2.&lt;/span&gt; Advanced Downhill Skier&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-4" id="text-1-0-2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
We will see all snow types. We will may be tired and carry heavy packs. We will
need to be able to safely circumnavigate objective hazards. We need to ski at
an advanced level.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org318bb6a" class="outline-4"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="org318bb6a"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-4"&gt;1.0.3.&lt;/span&gt; Experienced Winter Camper&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-4" id="text-1-0-3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Building a snow cave, choosing a safe campsite, having a dialed winter
sleeping system (down to about -30°C [-23°F]) are necessary skills.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org634b85c" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org634b85c"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt; Prerequisites for being a good partner&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-2"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org210c8ee" class="outline-4"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="org210c8ee"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-4"&gt;2.0.1.&lt;/span&gt; Avalanche Training&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-4" id="text-2-0-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I guide groups in all avalanche conditions, adjusting to safe terrain,
dependent on the group's abilities. I would welcome a role-based group
structure, and can comfortably take the role for assessing avalanche danger. I
make mistakes, and the more eyes looking at the conditions, the lesser the
chance of missing signs of danger. If you are an experienced winter
backcountry ski tourer, you should also have avalanche training. With my
experience mentoring successful tour guide aspirants, I feel I can help you
apply your training, but you need the fundamentals and experience first.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org5b74364" class="outline-4"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="org5b74364"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-4"&gt;2.0.2.&lt;/span&gt; Mental Strength Training&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-4" id="text-2-0-2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Winter is cold, windy and snowy. I love it, but it still can get to
me. Getting my butt kicked is part of the adventure. I can center myself with
meditation. I can forgive harshness, moodiness, etc. and go back to being a
relaxed provider of bad jokes. Centering oneself is a skill. You need to
also have this ability when I inevitably forget to be thankful and
open. Mental resilience is key when we get our butts kicked.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgfa69529" class="outline-4"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="orgfa69529"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-4"&gt;2.0.3.&lt;/span&gt; Physical conditioning&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-4" id="text-2-0-3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
We need to be consistently fast. The risk of an overuse injury, overtraining,
or of a ski injury due to fatigue is high. Carrying a heavy pack through deep
snow is hard work. Furthermore, we need to be similarly fast. Social tension
due to differing fitness is a problem. We should complete one of the &lt;a href="https://uphillathlete.com"&gt;Uphill
Athlete&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://evokeendurance.com"&gt;Evoke Endurance&lt;/a&gt; courses &lt;b&gt;together&lt;/b&gt;, at the very least.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="tips"/><category term="safety"/><category term="skills"/></entry><entry><title>The Remo Rub</title><link href="https://skitraverse.com/tips/the-remo-rub/" rel="alternate"/><published>2023-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-31T16:51:59.164533+02:00</updated><author><name>Brian J. Oney</name></author><id>tag:skitraverse.com,2023-01-01:/tips/the-remo-rub/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;div id="outline-container-org85b9edd" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org85b9edd"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; Problem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It's cold, and your skins aren't sticking to the base any more. Maybe you stored them in your jacket. Maybe your walked on sunny, but then shaded aspects. Maybe your skins partly loosened, for whatever reason, then accumulated snow, which transformed to ice.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-orgf739931" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgf739931"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt; The Remo Rub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-2"&gt;
&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Place …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;div id="outline-container-org85b9edd" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org85b9edd"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; Problem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It's cold, and your skins aren't sticking to the base any more. Maybe you stored them in your jacket. Maybe your walked on sunny, but then shaded aspects. Maybe your skins partly loosened, for whatever reason, then accumulated snow, which transformed to ice.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-orgf739931" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgf739931"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt; The Remo Rub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-2"&gt;
&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Place one end of your ski down in the snow, lean the other on your
shoulder, with the base facing away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pull the iced up sticky side of your skin over the exposed edges with a
fair bit of tension. The ice will scrape off and fall off. Also, this
roughens up the adhesive as well, so it adheres better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Problem fixed, at least for an hour or two.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Why does this work so well? The problem is usually not that the adhesive is
wet or cold. The problem is the layer of ice between your base and your
skins. Putting your skins in your coat only melts the ice or snow on
them. Some of this water then freezes onto the sticky surface when you reapply
your skins, causing or worsening the problem.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org60d4e32" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org60d4e32"&gt;&lt;span class="section-number-2"&gt;3.&lt;/span&gt; History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
An tour guide apprentice of mine, Remo S., improved on my old method of using a knife blade
to scratch the ice off the sticky base of climbing skins.  "Necessity is the mother
of all inventions." His approach? He got sick of asking for my knife and used
his splitboard's edge.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="tips"/><category term="skills"/></entry></feed>